kinsta.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy - Kinsta Performance WordPress Hosting

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Kinsta collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Kinsta’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Kinsta’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Kinsta may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Kinsta also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on Kinsta blogs. Kinsta only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Kinsta’s websites choose to interact with Kinsta in ways that require Kinsta to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Kinsta gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for WordPress hosting services at Kinsta.com to provide an email address. Those who engage in transactions with Kinsta – by purchasing access to the Akismet comment spam prevention service, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Kinsta collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Kinsta. Kinsta does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Kinsta discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Kinsta’s behalf or to provide services available at Kinsta’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Kinsta’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Kinsta will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Kinsta discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Kinsta believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Kinsta, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Kinsta website and have supplied your email address, Kinsta may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Kinsta and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Kinsta takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Kinsta uses cookies to help Kinsta identify and track visitors, their usage of Kinsta website, and their website access preferences. Kinsta visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Kinsta’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Kinsta’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Comments**

Comments and other content submitted to our Akismet anti-spam service are not saved on our servers unless they were marked as false positives, in which case we store them long enough to use them to improve the service to avoid future false positives.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Kinsta may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Kinsta’s sole discretion. Kinsta encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:  
Kinsta.com  
<https://kinsta.com/>  
_info@kinsta.com_  
This document was last updated on November 01, 2013
